Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen Photographs 5148 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen Photographs
1831-1968
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen (ORC&B)
5148 P
2.11 cubic feet
2.1 linear ft.
Photographs.
This collection of photographs include photographs taken at Division and Committee meetings as well as Membership Banquets and Ceremonies. Some of the Divisions represented in the photographs are: 42, 43, 91, 133, 135, 139, 180, 236, 248, 313, 339, 518, and 647.
8047369
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 10, 2010
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 07, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Order of Railway Conductors of America (ORC) was a labor union that represented train conductors in the United States. It has its origins in the Conductors Union founded in 1868. Later it extended membership to brakemen. In 1969 the ORC merged with three other unions to form the United Transportation Union.[wikipedia.org/wiki/Order_of_Railway_Conductors]
Scope and Contents
This collection of photographs include photographs taken at Division and Committee meetings as well as Membership Banquets and Ceremonies. Some of the Divisions represented in the photographs are: 42, 43, 91, 133, 135, 139, 180, 236, 248, 313, 339, 518, and 647.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5148: Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen Records 5148 MB: Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen Memorabilia 5754: Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen and Seaboard Airline Railroad Company General Committee of Adjustment Files 6289: Order of Railway Conductors Division 642 Records
Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen x Archives
8047369
- Association of General Chairmen- includes: officers in Chicago, Ill 1953, and GTW group picture. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- CAMA Meeting, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  August 1950 (Pittsburgh)
- Camp Claiborne, LA (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Cheyenne Meeting (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Christiansen, C. F. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Committee of Grievances and Appeals (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Committee on Officer Reports (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Conductors (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Congressional Candidates (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Delegations (Box 1, Folder 10)
  includes: Rock Island; Florida; Southern Railway; Eastern; Seaboard Airline Railroad; Canadian; and Texas
- Division 42, Entertainment Committee, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  31-May-41
- Division 43 Special Grand Division, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  September 2, 1946- includes: Transportation Committee; Committee on Officers Reports; Local Housing Committee; Codifying Committee; Special Caucus Committee; Jurisprudence Committee.
- Division 91, Portland, Oregon (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Division 133 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Division 135 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Division 139 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Division 180, Atlanta, Georgia (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Division 236 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Division 248, Sheffield, Alabama (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Division 313, Tucson, Arizona (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Division 339 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Division 518 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Division 647 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Emergency Board #154, Washington, DC, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  11-Apr-63
- Event In Ballroom (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Fifth Sunday Meeting, Macon, GA, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  29-Mar-53
- Field Representatives, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- 45th Grand Division (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Fraser, Harry Wilson, President (Box 1, Folder 29)
- General Committees, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  includes: General Committee of Adjustments, Delaware & Hudson Railroad; Great Northern General Committee, St Paul; B & O General Committee, April 1957; L & N General Committee, May 1957.
- General Secretary- Treasurers-includes: W. J Maxwell (Box 1, Folder 31)
- C. H Anderson; J. H. Rodgers, Cedar Rapids; G. H Oram. (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Grand Chief Conductors (1800s), 1869-1890 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  includes: Calvin S. Wheaton, Elmira, NY Div. 9, October 1880 to July 1890; Alfred G. Black, Crestline, Ohio, Div. No. 8, October 1869 to August 23, 1870.
- Grand Division, group photo (names are on photo), 1885 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Hobart, (BLE) Assistant Secretary of Labor (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Hughes and Ives, J.L. D (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Insurance Commissioners- John A. Scott, Grant Sonders, W. D. Johnson, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- International (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Leaders in Oregon (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Lechner, George (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Local Committees (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Meeting (President G. H. Harris, A. G. Wise, G. Cox, and others present) (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Membership Banquets and Ceremonies (Box 1, Folder 43)
  includes: Montreal banquet; Chicago Pullman Banquet; Knoxville Div. No 139; merit certificates to 4 retired Southern Railway conductors
- Men (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Milwaukee Railroad Lines East (Mr. Hughes and Mr. Kenney in photo) (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Missouri Pacific Gold Spike, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  Jul-57
- Mo Pac, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- ORC & B Convention (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Niesze, Chief Clerk (with Peg Oram and J. H. Rodgers) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Officers, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  includes Joint Associations, June 1953; Henry R. Nelson; C. A. Watson (Vice President), W. G. Baker (Canadian Vice President) Jake R. Wilson( Chairman, Grand Trustee). W. H. Jeffries (Grand Trustee), J. A. Bryant (Grand Trustee), Rudolph Froehlich (Grand
- ORC Home, Savannah, Georgia, 1929-1932 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Christmas Day 1929 and Visitors, 1932.
- ORC & B 100th Anniversary Banquet combined with 50th year celebration of CBAMA Chicago, Illinois, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  14-Jun-68
- ORC & B Association of General Committees President Harris with chairmen of Eastern West & Southeastern Districts of ORCB, Ross Keller, SE; John Wolf, Eastern; J W Kennedy, Western (Box 2, Folder 5)
- ORC & B Centennials, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  includes retirement dinner, centennial pageant at Sacramento to commemorate Southern Pacific's Western lines; 100th Anniversary Special on ICRR from Freeport, Illinois to Amboy, with an ICRR Depot dedication of marker, June 14- June 15, 1968
- Oram, G. H., General Secretary- Treasurer (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Order of Railway Conductors, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  includes: ORC Building, 1948 and Railway Labor Building.
- Perkins, Robert, Editor- ORCB (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Political Candidates (Box 2, Folder 10)
  includes: P. H. Tubin Williams, Texas State Legislative Representative; Congressman James E. Van Zandt, Pennsylvania.
- Port Richmond, PA (Box 2, Folder 11)
  general view of the world's largest privately owned tidewater terminal, and a photo of the Coal Dumps with capabilities of dumping forty cars per hour.
- Presidents (Box 2, Folder 12)
  includes: Fraser, G. H. Harris; Edward Patrick Curtis, Smithville, TX, Phillips; James Andrew Phillips; R O Hughes; Garretson
- Pullman Meeting- Pullman General Committee, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  2/5/53.
- Railroad Workers, 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  includes: Brakemen from Santa Fe RR Chillicothe, Ill, 1918; workers on local run between Streator and Pekin Ill. over the Toledo Peoria & Western, 1918; workers on Chicago & Northwestern RR, 1917.
- Rives (Box 2, Folder 15)
- ROE, with Brown and Lundborg, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- San Antonio Group (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Scott, John (Wagner) (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Sleeping Car Conductors Officers, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  (January 26, 1944): A. G. wise, Executive V-P; J L D Ives, V-P; R. R. Nicholas, V-P; M. H. Barney, V-P; B. C. Johnson, V-P; R. O Hughes, V-P; J. R. Kelly. Trustee; J. F. Casey, Trustee; J. A. Scott, Chairman, Trustees; J. H Rodgers, V-P; H. Fraser, Presid
- Southern Pacific Group (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Ten Man Club, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  includes: Milner, B. C. Johnson, G. Redrup, Downing, J. H. Irwin, P. J. Hilton, F. E. Renville, April 1954; Finkenburger, B. C. Johnson, C. H. Anderson, T. G. Burke, L. S. Smith, Frank Freeburg, J. F. Byrne, John Willman, K. C. McLane, Roy Hirscheimer, H.
- Texas Joint Railway Labor Legislative Board (Box 2, Folder 22)
  B. R. Cowan, (BRT Chairman), W. M. York (ORT Vice- Chairman); P. H. Tobin Williams (ORCB Sec.) E. F. Jergens (BLFE Treas.); C. F. Majors (BRS); H. O. Paul (BLE); R. R. Wheatley (BRO); Tom G. Hawkes (BMWE) and Clyde E. Johnson (Joint Board Public Relations
- Trains, 1831-1961 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  includes: Chicago Rail Fair, September 5, 1949; Engine 22, O & C RR; postcards of the Pennsylvania # 8218, 4/5/53 and Pennsylvania #4191, 11/12/58; First steam on the NYC 1831; postcard of the train wreck of train 7, Trout Lake, August 7, 1912 (x 4); Nove
- Trustees, 1934-1941 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  George H. Harris, Grand; Lee F. Dover, Grand; J. R. Kelley; Grand Division; J. A. Bryant, Grand; W. H. Jeffries, Grand, Jake R Williams, Chairman trustees; J. A. Scott, Grand Division; Wilson; J. F. Casey, Grand Div.; Henry Zimmerman, Grand, July 31, 1934
- Vice Presidents (Box 2, Folder 25)
  R. R. Nicholas; John F. Casey, Sr. V-P; James A. Paddock, Sr. V-P; W. D. Johnson, V-P and Nat'l Legislative Rep.; K. Hinks; Gannnou; Harry Fraser, Sr. V-P; Thomas A. Gregg; F. J. Williams; R. O. Hughes; B. C. Johnson; George W. Lange; A. W. Hair; J. E. Ma
- Wage Negotiations- Chicago, Ill., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  9/1/1941; A. [Alvanley] Johnston, Grand Chief Engineer, BLE; Carl Goff, Asst President BLFE; H. W. Fraser, President ORC; A. F. Whitney, President, BRT, and T. C. Cashen, President, SUNA.
- Washington, D. C. Office- W. D. Johnson & secretary; unidentified group of 4 men including Johnson. (Box 2, Folder 27)
- White House Conference, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  Feb-51
- Whitney, General Secretary and Treasurer (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Wise, A. G. Executive Vice President Sleeping Car Conductors (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Women, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  includes: General & Women's Group, B & O, Comm. Mtg. 1957, Hilton-Reicha-Hair; Mrs. Hazel Hand, President of the Ladies' Auxiliary; Mrs. M Rohm, secretary to Rochik; Peg Oram, Annabel Kurtz, Edith Stuart, Hazel Grady. Chas Winters; Nellie E. Douglas, Pres
- Workers- R W Rosenwinge, Fireman- Helper and G W Smith, Engineer Freeport, Ill., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  6/15/68.
- Oswego Harbor, with sailing vessels and bridges, Buffalo Creek Railroad Co., 1870 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Oversize photos: 13 photographs sorted out of the 'misc. photos' box stored over the mapcase (Box 4, Folder 1)
- PA. Lines West - Full General Comm. - Jan 27, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- District Meeting - O.R.C. - New England Hotel Manger - June 2, 1935; O.R.C. of America - Hist Grand Division, Toronto, Canada, May 1934 (Box 5OP)
  - panoramic photos - District Meeting - O.R.C. - New England Hotel Manger - June 2, 1935; O.R.C. of America - Hist Grand Division, Toronto, Canada, May 1934, 1934-1935 (Box 5OP, Folder 1)
- Images digitized from the collection. (Box 6)